Phone no:2269726000

Email:thomasebere119@gmail.com

Git-hub-https://github.com/Thommyebere/

### Hello.

# I'm Thomas Ebere

I am an experienced Product Specialist who is currently transitioning into the role of a Software Engineer. My time in Product Management exposed me to some limitations in a product team due to its specialization of roles. Knowing fully how to interpret requirements and even go further in empathizing with users, I have decided to bring in this skill into writing code. I believe this would influence every line of code I write as I would always ask myself, "how would this line help users?", "how can I make this block of code more efficient"?. Coupled with my theoretical background in Computer Science, I believe I can distinguish myself amongst the best engineers we have out there by making sure that any algorithm I create or write is efficient for the user/product in question. I just want to create products that make users happy.

Recently, I just completed my postgraduate studies at the University of Waterloo where I studied Electrical and Computer Engineering but specialized in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. My area of concentration was mostly on Data Science. It is no news that AI is infused in all we do right now but most importantly, being a product person, I geared towards making sure that users experience is well carted to and this can be done by understanding previous trends of users with the data available to us and making use that to influence business decisions such as what to build next, what features are not useful and a lot more.

## Skills

Python, Git, MySQL, Postgres, Mongodb, Metabase, Flask, Django, Sklearn, Keras.

# **Experience**

July 2018-September 2019

Seamfix Nigeria, Lagos - Product Manager/Business Analyst/Scrum master/Agile Coach

- Increased Team Velocity by 70%
- Managed two products (Iclocker & BioRegistra).
- Released iClocker mobile App (IOS).
- Developed integration processes of BioRegistra APIs to Nigerian Banks for Account verification and Validation.
- Facilitated Scrum meetings, Sprint planning meetings, Sprint Review and Retrospective meetings.
- Generated revenue of \$ 70000 for the company
- Reduced Technical debts by 45%

May 2017-August 2017

#### Airtel Nigeria, Lagos - *Intern*

 Worked with the network team to under study and understand the concept of packet switching and circuit switching, mobile packet backbone Network and Value-added services

# Automation and Engineering Academy, Nigeria - Independent Contractor

- Deployed and installed networking component at Yaba Tech institute of technology
- Attended Siemens training in Switzerland on Home Automation for Desigo Series.
- Trained 5<sup>th</sup> year students at the University of Ibadan on the skills acquired in the training at Siemens in Switzerland.
- Taught Academy students on how to program Programmable logic controllers(S7-1200)

#### **Personal Project**

- Online Store (Python, Postgresql)
- Online Banking system (Python, MongoDB)
- Voting System (Python, Sql)
- Online Blog (python, Flask, Sql, Html, Javascript)-web application
- URL Shortener (python, Flask, Sql,HTML,Hashids)-web application

# Education

January 2020 – Present

### University of Waterloo, Waterloo - Masters in Electrical and Computer Engineering

- Developed model to predict google stock prices using (python, LSTM, sklearn)
- Developed model for salary prediction (Linear Regression algorithm)
- Developed a sentiment Analysis model on IMDB dataset and twitter dataset(KNN,Kmeans,python)
- Applied feature engineering to a dataset to completely analyze the data(PCA,ISOMAP,LDA)
- Developed model to differentiate between, different heart diseases using CNN, sklearn, kereas
- Developed model to number prediction in images using MLP, CNN, Sklearn
- Performed dataset preprocessing process such as cleaning the dataset, looking for missing values, normalization, one hot encoding.
- Link to git-hub for projects

August 2014-June 2018

#### Babcock University, Nigeria-Bachelors of Computer Science

- Babcock University Election Software (PHP,Laravel)(Project Manager)
- Student Grievance Redress System (PHP) (Project Manager)
- Online Book recommendation system using collaborative filtering (PHP, project Manager)
- Driver Drowsiness Detection System (Arduino)
- Online Event Management System (PHP, SQL) (Project Manager)

September 2008-July 2014

Senior Secondary School Certificate: The Crown College